# Mohamed Rafiq. A

N-block No:269 27th Street, Anna Nagar East, Chennai 600 012, Tamil Nadu.

Mobile: +91-9003083655 | Email: rafig.cryztal@gmail.com

## **Objective**

To be employed as a Web Developer where I could transform my proven programming Skills into real-time industrial practice thereby continuing to accumulate more Technical knowledge and experience working together with professionals. Currently involved in web development, with a total experience of 1.5 years.

#### **Education**

2013–2017 Bachelor of Engineering Degree

CGPA: 6.2

Major: Computer Science

**Institution:** Dhaanish Ahmed College of Engineering

University: Anna University, Chennai, India.

**Area of Interest**: Web Development, User Interface & Web Mining.

2012–2013 Higher Secondary School Certificate – XII Standard

Aggregate: 65%

**Institution:** Valliammal Matriculation Higher Secondary School,

Chennai, India.

Board: Tamil Nadu State Board.

2010–2011 Senior Secondary School Certificate –X Standard

Aggregate: 75%

Institution: Valliammal Matriculation Higher Secondary School,

Chennai. India.

Board: Tamil Nadu State Board.

# **Employment History**

Period Designation Organization

May 2017 - Oct 2018 Web Developer Cryztal Technologies, Chennai

# Conferences/Seminars/Workshops/Training Attended

- Attended a workshop on Ethical Hacking, by Microsoft Community 2016.
- Attended a Value-added course on Java in Zuvier Infotech Solutions 2017.

**Programming**: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Familiar with Bootstrap,

**Tools** Eclipse, Notepad++

Platforms: Microsoft Windows 2000/XP/7/8/10 & Linux

**Database**: Getting familiar in SQL.

**Office Automation**: Microsoft Office

## **Project History**

#### July 2017 - Dec 2017

Whales Cloud Soft

• Client: A School Administrative Tool Provider

Role: Web Developer

Responsibilities:

- Coding Creating Prototypes, creating interactive & responsive webpages based on Wireframes, Visual specification and style guide documents. Working with application development team to integrate front end with application backend.
- Unit Testing Creating test cases, executing unit testing and Browser compatibility testing.
- Defect Fixing Functional and Browser specific defects.
- Self Reviews and Review Comments Incorporation.
- Miscellaneous JS/CSS bundling, CMS related work.
- Technologies: HTML, CSS, AngularJS, & Bootstrap Frameworks

#### Feb 2018 - June 2018

BabHoney

- **Client**: Honey Selling company
- **Description**: E-Commerce based Website, working on payment gateway interaction between CC Avenue and Client's Banking account.
- Role: Content Management Expert
- Responsibilities:
  - Web Content Management System.
  - Adding e-commerce products.
  - Working Carting System
  - o Unit Testing
  - Test Plan/Case preparation
  - o Self Reviews and Review Comments Incorporation.
- Technologies: Html5, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, Web Content Management, WordPress & SQL.

## **Engineering Project Work**

Title: An Effective Trust Management System to scrutinize

Attacks Using Credibility Mode

Technology: JAVA, SQL

Industry: Dhaanish Ahmed college of engineering, India

#### Personal Profile

Date of Birth, Sex and

Marital Status: 8th May 1996, Male, Single

**Languages Known:** English & Tamil

Interests: Reading Books and Magazines, Computer Gaming,

Internet Surfing, World Affairs, Learning New

Languages.

#### **About Myself:**

- A Self-paced learner, highly adaptive to anything concerning computers, may it be Hardware or software.
- Ability to work under deadline durations and in team environments.
- Capability to learn any new technology as per the requirements and criteria using books and the Internet as guidance.
- Good Communication skills.

### **DECLARATION**

I, hereby declare that the above-mentioned particulars are true to my knowledge and I make this declaration consistentiously believing the same to be true.

PLACE: CHENNAI YOURS FAITHFULLY,

Date: (Mohamed Rafiq. A)